<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HHI on Daniel Scarnecchia</title>
    <link>/categories/hhi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HHI on Daniel Scarnecchia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/hhi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tech Ethics Won&#39;t Save Us</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/19/tech-ethics-won-t-save-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/19/tech-ethics-won-t-save-us/</guid>
      <description>This week, both Apple and Google have come under fire for continuing to allow sales of a Saudi government app which will enable men to track and manage the women under their guardianship from their app stores. This app effectively makes it easier for men to monitor and restrict the activities of their female relatives, including constraining their ability to travel freely. At the same time, the humanitarian sector is alarmed by the World Food Programme’s decision to engage the data analytics firm Palantir in a 5-year deal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Information Power Politics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/17/international-information-power-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/17/international-information-power-politics/</guid>
      <description>An overextended superpower is brought low in an era of ideological polarization, set against the backdrop of a widely adopted new technology which has radically transformed people’s relationship with information. Over 10 percent of the population dies in the subsequent conflicts. This isn’t a dark portent of a potential future. It’s a lesson from our past about the dangers that can arise when technology and politics intersect.
Thomas Cole, The Course of Empire—Destruction, 1836 via Wikimedia Commons</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humanitarianism’s other technology problem</title>
      <link>/post/2018/04/02/humanitarianism-s-other-technology-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/04/02/humanitarianism-s-other-technology-problem/</guid>
      <description>John Singer Sargent: Orestes Pursued by the Furies (1921) via Wikimedia Commons
For the first time in history, war and the attendant human suffering are occurring in societies connected to mobile internet–and subsequently entering the public consciousness in new ways. Aspects of war and conflict that were once near-invisible to those outside the war zone are now visible world-wide on social media platforms. People far away from the battlefield can now interact with and impact conflict in unprecedented and unexpected ways.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
