<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Scarnecchia</title>
<link>https://scarnecchia.net/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://scarnecchia.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.1.189</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Pizza alla romana</title>
  <dc:creator>D. Scarnecchia</dc:creator>
  <link>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/pizza-alla-romana/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>A specification, translated from Italian. The preparation of the Roman-style pizza by the slice requires attention and attention to detail.</p>
<section id="ingredients" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<table class="table">
<caption>Ingredients for one (1) 30 Pizza</caption>
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th style="text-align: left;">Amount</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Percentage</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">360 g</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">100 %</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">flour (0 or 00)</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">290 g</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">80.5 %</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">water (at 4° C)</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">7 g</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">2 %</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">salt</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">7 g</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">2 %</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">extra virgin olive oil</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">2.1 g</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">.5 %</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">yeast</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="preparation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="preparation">Preparation</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>In a mixer (or in a container large enough for those who proceed by hand, pour the flour, the crumbled brewer’s yeast and then the salt, starting to mix.</li>
<li>Add 75 % (217.5 g) of the water at 4° C (39.2° F) and start working the dough carefully, until it is strung. The dough is “strung” when it detaches from the walls and bottom of the mixer and is compact , smooth and elastic.</li>
<li>Only when the dough has these characteristics can the remaining part of water be added little by little (always at 4 °), waiting every time that the pizza dough has completely absorbed the remaining amount of water.</li>
</ol>
<p>Rest at room temperature:</p>
<table class="table">
<caption>Autolyse times based on room temperature</caption>
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th style="text-align: left;">Room Temperature</th>
<th>Autolyse Time</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">24–26° C (75–79° F)</td>
<td>30 minutes</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">21–23° C (69–74° F)</td>
<td>60 minutes</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">18–20° C (64–68° F)</td>
<td>90 minutes</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Leaven in an airtight container for 44 hours at 4° C (39.2° F).</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Pour into a floured baking sheet and fold into three.</li>
<li>Let rest for 3–4 hours</li>
<li>Pre-heat the oven to maximum temperature</li>
<li>Roll out into a rectangular shape and top with oil</li>
<li>Transfer to pan and top with everything but the mozzarella</li>
<li>Cook for 6 minutes at maximum temperature at the bottom of the oven.</li>
<li>Lower temperature to 230° C (450° F), add mozzarella, and cook for an additional ten minutes.</li>
</ol>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>cooking</category>
  <category>pizza</category>
  <category>recipes</category>
  <category>italian</category>
  <guid>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/pizza-alla-romana/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Messer Agnolotto</title>
  <dc:creator>D. Scarnecchia</dc:creator>
  <link>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/messer-agnolotto/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This recipe was shared with me by my cousin <a href="https://dettiefumetti.wordpress.com/category/cucina/">Filippo Novelli</a>. I have translated it from Italian and posted it here for my reference.</p>
<section id="sec-egg-pasta" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-egg-pasta">Egg Pasta</h2>
<section id="sec-ingredients" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-ingredients">Ingredients</h3>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Amount</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>300 g</td>
<td>flour</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>3</td>
<td>eggs</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="sec-directions" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-directions">Directions</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Roll out dough and cut in the shape of a ravioli</li>
<li>Stuff with ricotta, grated peccorino, and black pepper</li>
<li>Rest for one (1) hour at room temperature</li>
<li>Cook for four (4) minutes in boiling salted water</li>
</ol>
<p>Separately prepare the sauce with butter, sage, guanciale, and pepper.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>cooking</category>
  <category>pasta</category>
  <category>recipes</category>
  <category>italian</category>
  <guid>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/messer-agnolotto/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tonkotsu Ramen</title>
  <dc:creator>D. Scarnecchia</dc:creator>
  <link>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/tonkotsu-ramen/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This recipe is a pressure cooker adaptation of Kenji Lopez-Alt’s Serious Eat’s recipe via Reddit user Lord Ramen. The original can be found in all it’s glory under the post <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ramen/comments/7arli8/fresh_dont_feel_like_spending_18_hours_making/">“[FRESH] Don’t feel like spending 18 hours making tonkotsu? Use a pressure cooker and spend 6 hours instead.”</a>.</p>
<p>I have reproduced it here for my own reference.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>I’ve been exploring the idea of altering my tonkotsu recipe. Right now that takes too long for most people to try it, and it’s really involved. 18 hours! Too long!</p>
<p>The thing is, home cooks aren’t alone in this hatred of double-day cookathons. Restaurants also have this problem after all. So many have opted for cooking Tonkotsu in a pressure cooker. They make massive, hundred quart pressure cookers in Japan for this very reason.</p>
<p>I won’t get into the chemistry of pressure cooking (there are people far more eloquent out there who have written about it extensively), but the gist of it is that pressure cookers increase the boiling point of water due to the pressure in the pot, allowing you to cook things way faster in a moist environment. A broth that takes 6 hours now only takes 1.</p>
<p>Now, the legendary J. Kenji Lopez Alt (/u/j_kenji_lopez-alt), when he wrote his tonkotsu recipe that often gets cited here, wrote very explicitly that a pressure cooker wouldn’t work for tonkotsu. A pressure cooker doesn’t jostle and actually bubble (the pressure in the pot prevents a rapid boil), which is integral to the emulsification of the fat and water in a tonkotsu.</p>
<p>Except… well… you can totally cook a tonkotsu in a pressure cooker. Sorry Kenji. You just need to get that rapid boil in at some point, which you can do after the bulk pressure cooking. The gelatin will work pretty quickly to emulsify things together.</p>
<p>So here’s the method. I don’t think this is perfect yet, but I thought I’d share as an alternative to having a pot on the fire for 18 hours. For the other components, I’ve also included them in the bottom.</p>
</blockquote>
<section id="broth" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="broth">Broth</h2>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Ingredient</th>
<th>Amount</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Pork Neck Bones</td>
<td>1 kg / 2 lbs</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Pork Femurs</td>
<td>1 kg / 2 lbs</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Fatback</td>
<td>180 g / .4 lbs</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Onion</td>
<td>½</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Garlic</td>
<td>6 cloves</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<section id="directions" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="directions">Directions</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li><em>Optional</em>: The night before, or at least 6 hours prior to cooking, soak your neck bones and femurs in water in a cold, non-reactive vessel.<sup>1</sup></li>
<li>When ready to cook, add your neck bones and femurs to a pot with fresh water. Bring to a boil, then down to a simmer, and skim the scum that rises to the top of the pot. Do this for 15-20 minutes, or until little scum is rising. The scum goes through several phases here, you’ll know when the scum is pretty much done rising up. This blanch is integral for a white tonkotsu, don’t skip it, and don’t end it prematurely.</li>
<li>Strain the bones from the blanching liquid. Discard the liquid.</li>
<li>Scrub and clean the bones under running water, removing any black or dirty looking particulate that may be on the outside of the bones or in crevices.</li>
<li>Add your now clean bones to a pressure cooker, covering with just enough water. Bring to a boil, then cover, bring to full pressure (15 PSI), and cook under pressure for 2 hours</li>
<li>Fast release the pot, being careful to avoid splashes (if your pressure cooker doesn’t have this feature, regular release is fine). Give the contents a stir, then cover, bring to high pressure again, and cook for 1 hour.</li>
<li>Remove pressure and open the cooker. Add in your fatback, give it a stir, bring the contents back to a boil, and cook under pressure for one more hour.</li>
<li>Depressurize the pot. Remove the fatback, adding it to a blender. Blend with an appropriate amount of broth until the fatback is completely broken down into a liquid, then add this back to the broth. No chunks here, we’re looking for smooth liquid.</li>
<li>If using, add aromatics to the now uncovered broth</li>
<li>Cook, uncovered, at a rapid boil, for 45 minutes, or until the broth is opaque, creamy, and to the desired consistency you want. Stir occasionally to prevent scorching on the bottom of the pot.</li>
<li>Strain and reserve as needed. Conversely, store in the fridge for up to 5 days, or freeze for several months.</li>
</ol>
</section>
</section>
<section id="chashu" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="chashu">Chashu</h2>
<p>High temp sous vide chashu. You SHOULD do this, it’s a nice balance between braised and steaky, tender but not overly-melty. And it’s pretty easy.</p>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Ingredient</th>
<th>Amount</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Pork belly, skin on</td>
<td>tbd</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Mirin</td>
<td>½ C</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Soy Sauce</td>
<td>½ C</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Water</td>
<td>1 C</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Brown Sugar</td>
<td>1 T</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Sake</td>
<td>¼ C</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<section id="directions-1" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="directions-1">Directions</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Preheat the waterbath to 174° F.</li>
<li>Sear the pork belly on all sides in a pan until golden brown, then place in vacuum bag.</li>
<li>Deglaze the pan with the remaining ingredients, then reserve this liquid and allow to cool.</li>
<li>When liquid has cooled, add it to the bag with the pork.</li>
<li>Cook the pork belly sous vide for a minimum seven (7) hours, or up to twelve (12) hours.<sup>2</sup></li>
<li>Remove from the bath, and shock in ice water to chill quickly. Reserve in the fridge if needed.</li>
</ol>
</section>
</section>
<section id="low-hydration-noodles" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="low-hydration-noodles">Low Hydration Noodles</h2>
<p>Lord Ramen’s editorial note:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I made some really low hydration noodles for this one, which I cannot recommend making. 30% hydration. They were awesome. And impossible to make at home. Don’t make these. You’ll hate yourself. Seriously don’t make this recipe. Just buy the noodles from Sun Noodle. They’re quite good.</p>
</blockquote>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Ingredient</th>
<th>Amount</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>00 Flour</td>
<td>99 g</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Vital Wheat Gluten</td>
<td>1 g</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>Salt</td>
<td>1 g</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>Dry Kansui</td>
<td>1 g</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<section id="directions-2" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="directions-2">Directions</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Add kansui powder and salt to the water, dissolve completely. I like to add one at a time, these alkaline salts actually release a small amount of heat when hitting the water and will form small chemical bonds to themselves if not added gradually, which results in it clumping up. Go slowly, stir constantly until clear. This will take awhile, but eventually things will work out.</li>
<li>In a standing mixer with a paddle attachment, add your flour, Turn the mixer to “stir” and run for 30 seconds.</li>
<li>While running the mixer on stir, add two thirds of your water mixture slowly, in an even stream. Let the mixer stir for 3 minutes.</li>
<li>Add in the remaining water mixture with the mixer running, run for another minute, until small clumps begin to form.</li>
<li>Add the mixture to a ziplock style bag. Close, and let this rest for 30 minutes. This gives the flour granules time to fully absorb the water and alkaline salts, rests some gluten (which, believe it or not, you developed while mixing this dough) and allows some trapped air in the dough balls to escape, which is called “degassing.” An air free starch gel results in better texture. Don’t skip this.</li>
<li>Knead it. For these really low hydration ones, I did the stepping technique, then rolled. As in, put the plastic bag on the floor, and step on the contents until it sticks together. Then take a chunk of this thick sheet, and roll it out with your machine, going through the largest setting, then the 2nd, then the 3rd. Fold, making sure to fold to keep the direction of the dough consistent, repeating this process. until the sheet is quite smooth and not ragged. This process sucks. Again, don’t do this recipe. It’s hard.</li>
<li>After kneading, cover with plastic, and rest at room temp for another 30 minutes. This gives the gluten time to relax.</li>
<li>Pull out your dough. Portion into workable sizes, and roll out to desired thickness, using potato or cornstarch as you go to prevent sticking. Do this with a pasta machine, it is borderline impossible without a machine. An electric one will save you an incredible amount of effort.</li>
<li>Cut your noodles to your desired thickness. I used an angel hair attachment, so they were quite thin here.</li>
<li>Place in the fridge and allow to rest for at least a day. This final resting phase ensures even hydration and helps make an even starch gel, promoting better texture. Enzymatic activity in the flour also helps build flavor, and the alkaline flavor of the dough subsides somewhat.</li>
</ol>


</section>
</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>In retrospect, I would reverse the ratios for the alkaline salts. Potassium makes the noodles very firm, making them even harder to work with at home. I spoke with a Kansui manufacturer on this and they suggested high sodium levels are common in Hakata-style noodles for this reason.↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>In retrospect, I would reverse the ratios for the alkaline salts. Potassium makes the noodles very firm, making them even harder to work with at home. I spoke with a Kansui manufacturer on this and they suggested high sodium levels are common in Hakata-style noodles for this reason.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>recipes</category>
  <category>ramen</category>
  <category>japanese</category>
  <guid>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/tonkotsu-ramen/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Stuffed Clams</title>
  <dc:creator>D. Scarnecchia</dc:creator>
  <link>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/stuffed-clams/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="ingredients" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Amount</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>18–24</td>
<td>Littleneck Clams</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>¼ lbs</td>
<td>butter</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>3 T</td>
<td>Shallot (finely chopped)</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>1 t</td>
<td>Minced garlic</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>¼ C</td>
<td>Fresh parsley</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>1 T</td>
<td>Fresh basil</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>1 C</td>
<td>Bread crumbs</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>8 T</td>
<td>Grated parmesan</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>2 T</td>
<td>Dry white wine</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>¼ C</td>
<td>Chopped prosciutto</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>¼ t</td>
<td>Red pepper flakes</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>taste</td>
<td>salt and pepper</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>2 T</td>
<td>Olive oil</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="directions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="directions">Directions</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Preheat oven to 425 F</li>
<li>Shuck clams</li>
<li>Process clams in food processor (but do not over process)</li>
<li>In saucepan, combine clams with butter, shallots, garlic, parsley, basil, breadcrumbs, 6 T cheese, wine, prosciutto, pepper flakes, salt and pepper</li>
<li>Cook until well blended</li>
<li>Stuff shells</li>
<li>Sprinkle with cheese and olive oil</li>
<li>Bake 15 minutes</li>
<li>Broil for final minute</li>
</ol>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>seafood</category>
  <category>clams</category>
  <category>christmas</category>
  <guid>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/stuffed-clams/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Double Chocolate Crinkle Cookies</title>
  <dc:creator>D. Scarnecchia</dc:creator>
  <link>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/chocolate-crinkle-cookies/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><em>Prep Time</em>: 2 hours, 30 minutes<br>
<em>Cook Time</em>: 11 minutes<br>
<em>Total Time</em>: 2 hours, 45 minutes<br>
<em>Yield</em>: 20 cookies</p>
<section id="ingredients" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<table class="table">
<caption>Cookie Ingredients</caption>
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Amount</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>125 g</td>
<td>all-purpose flour (spoon &amp; leveled)</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>53 g</td>
<td>unsweetened natural cocoa powder</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>1 t</td>
<td>baking soda</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>⅛ t</td>
<td>salt</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>1 stick (115 g)</td>
<td>unsalted butter, softened to room temperature</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>100 g</td>
<td>granulated sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>100 g</td>
<td>packed light or dark brown sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>1</td>
<td>large egg at room temperature</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>1 t</td>
<td>pure vanilla extract</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>180 g</td>
<td>mini or regular size semi-sweet chocolate chips</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<table class="table">
<caption>Sugar Coating</caption>
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Amount</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>35 g</td>
<td>granulated sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>120 g</td>
<td>confectioner’s sugar</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="directions" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="directions">Directions</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Whisk the flour, cocoa powder, baking soda, and salt together in a large bowl. Set aside.</li>
<li>In a large bowl using a hand-held mixer or stand mixer fitted with a paddle attachment, beat the butter, granulated sugar, and brown sugar together on medium high speed until fluffy and creamed, about 2 minutes. Beat in egg and vanilla on high speed. Scrape down the sides and bottom of the bowl as needed.</li>
<li>On low speed, slowly mix the dry ingredients into the wet ingredients until combined, then beat in the chocolate chips. The cookie dough will be thick and sticky. Cover dough tightly with aluminum foil or plastic wrap and chill for at least 2 hours and up to 3 days.<sup>1</sup></li>
<li>Remove cookie dough from the refrigerator and allow to sit at room temperature for 15 minutes. You can preheat the oven during this time.</li>
<li>Preheat oven to 350°F (177°C). Line two large baking sheets with parchment paper or silicone baking mats. Set aside.</li>
<li>Scoop and roll balls of dough, about 1.5 Tablespoons of dough each, into balls. Roll each ball very lightly in granulated sugar, then generously in the confectioners’ sugar. Place 3 inches apart on the baking sheets.</li>
<li>Bake the cookies for 11-12 minutes. If the cookies aren’t really spreading by minute 9, remove them from the oven and lightly bang the baking sheet on the counter 2-3x. This helps initiate that spread. Return to the oven for a couple more minutes. The cookies will be thick regardless, though—they deflate a little as they cool!</li>
<li>Cool cookies for 5 minutes on the baking sheet, then transfer to a wire rack to cool completely.</li>
<li>Cookies stay fresh covered at room temperature for up to 1 week.</li>
</ol>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Chilling is absolutely necessary for this recipe.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>dessert</category>
  <category>cookies</category>
  <category>christmas</category>
  <guid>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/chocolate-crinkle-cookies/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Chocolate Layer Cookie (Mint Brownies)</title>
  <dc:creator>D. Scarnecchia</dc:creator>
  <link>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/chocolate-layer-cookie/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="brownie-layer" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="brownie-layer">Brownie Layer</h2>
<section id="ingredients" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ingredients">Ingredients</h3>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Amount</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>2 squares</td>
<td>Unsweetened chocolate</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>½ C</td>
<td>Butter</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>2</td>
<td>Eggs</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>1 C</td>
<td>Sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>½ C</td>
<td>Flour</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="directions" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="directions">Directions</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Preheat oven to 350 F.</li>
<li>Grease Rectangular Pan</li>
<li>Melt unsweetened chocolate and butter in a bain-marie</li>
<li>Beat eggs and sugar until thick</li>
<li>Add flour and chocolate mix and stir until smooth</li>
<li>Pour batter into pan and bake for 25 minutes.</li>
</ol>
</section>
</section>
<section id="mint-cream-layer" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="mint-cream-layer">Mint Cream Layer</h2>
<section id="ingredients-1" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ingredients-1">Ingredients</h3>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Amount</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>1 ½ C</td>
<td>Confectioner’s sugar</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>3 T</td>
<td>Butter</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>2 T</td>
<td>Heavy cream</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>¾ t</td>
<td>Mint extract</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="directions-1" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="directions-1">Directions</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Beat ingredients until smooth. Add green food coloring.</li>
</ol>
</section>
</section>
<section id="chocolate-glaze" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="chocolate-glaze">Chocolate Glaze</h2>
<section id="ingredients-2" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ingredients-2">Ingredients</h3>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th>Amount</th>
<th>Ingredient</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td>2 oz</td>
<td>Sweetened chocolate</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td>2 T</td>
<td>Butter</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td>1 t</td>
<td>Vanilla extract</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="directions-2" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="directions-2">Directions</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Melt chocolate and butter together in bain-marie</li>
<li>Stir in vanilla</li>
</ol>
</section>
</section>
<section id="assembly" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="assembly">Assembly</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Allow brownie layer to cool to room temperature</li>
<li>Spread mint cream over brownie and chill for one hour</li>
<li>After cooling, drizzle chocolate glaze over mint cream.</li>
<li>Chill until firm</li>
</ol>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>dessert</category>
  <category>brownies</category>
  <category>christmas</category>
  <guid>https://scarnecchia.net/recipes/chocolate-layer-cookie/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mapping Medfield State Hospital</title>
  <dc:creator>D. Scarnecchia</dc:creator>
  <link>https://scarnecchia.net/posts/mapping-medfield-state/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This weekend <a href="http://faineg.com">Faine</a> and I drove out to the Medfield State Hospital, a defunct mental hospital in Medfield, Massachusetts. The grounds are open to the public, and it is outside of Boston’s Class B airspace. Faine recently picked up a <a href="http://www.dji.com/product/phantom-3">DJI Phantom 3</a> and a the folks at <a href="https://www.dronedeploy.com">Drone Deploy</a> were kind enough to give us access to the application for testing.</p>
<p>This map is generated with orthorectified imagery by Drone Deploy. In all the process of collecting the photographs took about 7 minutes. It has a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ground_sample_distance">ground sample distance</a><sup>1</sup> of 3.2 cm and covers about 12.2 hectares of land:</p>
<iframe style="width: 100%; height: 100%;" src="medfield.html"></iframe>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>See also: <a href="../../resources/GSD_Calculator/index.html">GSD Calculator</a>↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>Drones</category>
  <category>Mapping</category>
  <category>GIS</category>
  <guid>https://scarnecchia.net/posts/mapping-medfield-state/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://scarnecchia.net/posts/mapping-medfield-state/resources/img/ortho_merged.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
